<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gregg Bernstein | gregg.io</title>
    <description>User &amp;amp; Product Researcher &amp;bull; Writer &amp;amp; Editor &amp;bull; Speaker &amp;amp; Educator
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 22:18:13 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 22:18:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Field Test</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.studiodradiodurans.com/&quot;&gt;Jan Chipchase&lt;/a&gt; is an authority on qualitative product research. He embeds himself in the field with a team of colleagues and fixers, capturing the context and ecosystems in which people live. He’s the type of researcher I want to be when I grow up—traveling to the far corners of the earth to uncover hidden truths and potential opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan’s taken his experiences and created the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/janchipchase/the-field-study-handbook&quot;&gt;Field Study Handbook&lt;/a&gt;. It was a career highlight to work with Jan as a technical reviewer on a few chapters of the handbook, and I’m excited for the book’s release in June, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we get closer to the book’s launch, I contributed a short piece about what you learn about a product research team in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The field, though, is opportunity. Exiting the office and entering the field introduces novelty, variety, and a chance for adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-field-study-handbook/the-field-test-5a243e71ff35&quot;&gt;The Field Test&lt;/a&gt; on Medium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/field.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/field.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UX Research Templates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Vox Product blog, I wrote about how I create an &lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2017/4/19/15309792/ambient-ux-research&quot;&gt;ambient awareness of user and product research&lt;/a&gt; across my product team by sharing everything, everywhere—repeatedly and redundantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my sharing takes place over Slack and in Google Docs, and a few people asked me to &lt;strong&gt;share my research doc templates&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I share notes from a single interview or usability test in Slack, I keep things simple with a bolded headline and a handful of bullet points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/slack_template.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of how I share quick takeaways in Slack.&quot; title=&quot;An example of how I share quick takeaways in Slack.&quot; /&gt;
I want my colleagues to be aware of what I just learned, and who I learned it from. I try to anonymize participants in Slack by only referring to their role, not their name. Because I work with many internal users, I want to avoid bringing undue attention on any one person. (I also want to avoid interrupting their work by inadvertently summoning them to the Slack channel!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-doc&quot;&gt;Google Doc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to collecting findings into a more permanent document, I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1yuTzHv47qCRbqbcdzu8subZpbKXfCXNglsvkjCYIM-w/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;this Google Doc template&lt;/a&gt; as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep reports as brief as possible, and open the doc with &lt;strong&gt;recommendations and issues&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s what people want to see, so why make them work to find it? Placing the recommendations at the top also makes it possible to review the findings by previewing (rather than opening) the file in Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google_template.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of how I structure takeaways in Google Docs.&quot; title=&quot;An example of how I structure takeaways in Google Docs.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then explain how I tested (remotely or IRL; with a prototype or something that’s been released) and recap each individual test or interview (almost verbatim from what I shared in Slack, perhaps with a few more details).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I use a &lt;strong&gt;Metadata&lt;/strong&gt; section to share the project genesis, goals, methodology, participants, script, schedule, and recruiting pitches. The metadata is meant to allow anyone to follow my steps, validate my work, or repeat the research process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This metadata section will look familiar to anyone who’s seen Tomer Sharon’s wonderful &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2012/01/ux-research-plan-stakeholders-love/&quot;&gt;UX Research Plan That Stakeholders Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;—I folded in a modified version of Tomer’s plan so this doc can serve as a proposal, a plan, or an archive depending on the stage of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alignment&quot;&gt;Alignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listed Slack and Google Docs as the media of choice for my organization. The important thing to note is that the medium you use is entirely dependent on your organization’s habits. If your org runs on Basecamp, or a combination of HipChat + Confluence, go that route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you’ll want to dismantle these templates and reassemble them to serve and inform your particular colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-me&quot;&gt;@ Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to see how different organizations capture and share information. If you have templates or recommendations you want to share, tweet at or email me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/25/templates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/25/templates.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ambient Research</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Vox Product blog, I describe how I create an &lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2017/4/19/15309792/ambient-ux-research&quot;&gt;ambient awareness of user and product research&lt;/a&gt; across my product team by sharing everything, everywhere—repeatedly and redundantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By showing my work everywhere and often, my colleagues see that research isn’t a “when we have the time” activity—it’s habitual and ongoing. Ideally, every project should bake in research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear to me that sharing findings in a way that makes them discoverable and teachable across an organization is the biggest challenge research teams face. Expect more thoughts on containing research in upcoming posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2017/4/19/15309792/ambient-ux-research&quot;&gt;Read the entire post on the Vox Product blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/ambient.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/ambient.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capture the Context</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Optimal Workshop blog, I explain that there’s so much more to interviews than asking and answering in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.optimalworkshop.com/capture-the-context-pro-tips-for-user-interviews&quot;&gt;Capture the Context&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stories convey so much. The best stories contain enough rich, lived-in detail to elicit understanding and empathy. These contextual details flesh out words and actions, anchoring the story in place and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.optimalworkshop.com/capture-the-context-pro-tips-for-user-interviews&quot;&gt;Read the entire post on the Optimal Workshop blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 06:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/30/capture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/30/capture.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Parts Bin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you propose something to your colleagues, but it’s not met with much enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a good design isn’t quite good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes a great idea works well on its own but not in concert with other parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could choose to see these as setbacks or disappointments. &lt;em&gt;Or you could see them as parts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when I worked at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;, I was introduced to the concept of the &lt;strong&gt;parts bin&lt;/strong&gt; by our CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/benchestnut&quot;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;. To Ben, every design or prototype held merit, regardless of whether it amounted to anything. At some point, those half-baked designs would become valuable in service to even better ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts bin became a research mindset for me and others at the company, as evidenced by our adoption of Evernote as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/connected-ux&quot;&gt;repository for anything research-related&lt;/a&gt;. A stray data point might not be useful today, but we figured it would be useful to &lt;em&gt;someone, someday&lt;/em&gt;. As I’ve written before, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gregg.io/2016/07/07/everything.html&quot;&gt;everything is important&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts bin applies beyond design and research. When you frame your ideas as parts to be broken down and reconfigured time and time again, they become less precious and more practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to hold onto them, and come up with a bin that works. Without the bin to document your ideas, parts will disappear into the ether. To that end, I want to share how I’ve set up my parts bin (or &lt;em&gt;bins&lt;/em&gt;, in my case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideas-and-inputs&quot;&gt;Ideas and Inputs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I break my parts bins across two dimensions: &lt;strong&gt;ideas and inputs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I have an &lt;strong&gt;idea&lt;/strong&gt;, I’m excited and need to capture it in a way that’s lightweight and actionable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I come across context for an idea—be it an article, data visualization, document, or whatever—that’s an &lt;strong&gt;input&lt;/strong&gt; that I need to tag and archive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ideas, I rely on Wunderlist. This app allows me to keep multiple lists, with each list affording subtasks and a notes field. I keep a lot of lists, including people to talk to, articles to read, and posts I want to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the latter, I have dozens of writing ideas. Each idea typically contains a few points I want to make, along with a sentence (or a string of words) to help me remember the context in which I came up with the idea. For this post, the list looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wl.png&quot; alt=&quot;This list hints at the structural pieces for this post—Ben at MailChimp, Wunderlist, Evernote, etc.&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot of Wunderlist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lean on Evernote for inputs. For instance, I’ve been studying cognitive interviews lately—a technique wonderfully documented in this recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2016/05/how-to-interrogate-suspects/&quot;&gt;Wired article&lt;/a&gt;. As I come across more literature on this topic, into my Evernote notebooks it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two repositories, or &lt;em&gt;parts bins&lt;/em&gt;, give me dozens of starting points and hundreds of supporting documents. And with a mindset that all of this will—in some way—prove useful, it’s a rewarding habit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 09:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/20/parts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/11/20/parts.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Research Resources</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m often asked my favorite research resources, so I’ve put together a very brief list of go-to books and articles. These are suitable for researchers, designers, or product managers of any level of expertise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abookapart.com/products/just-enough-research&quot;&gt;Just Enough Research&lt;/a&gt;: Erika Hall masterfully explains the elements of research as they relate to products, design, and users.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/interviewing-users/&quot;&gt;Interviewing Users&lt;/a&gt;: Talking to users is essential to build the right products for the right audience, and Steve Portigal demonstrates how to do it right.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howtomakesenseofanymess.com/&quot;&gt;How to Make Sense of Any Mess&lt;/a&gt;: Research is information, and Abby Covert organizes it in ways that help frame and solve messy problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://library.gv.com/tagged/user-research&quot;&gt;Google Ventures User Research Library&lt;/a&gt;: Stories, documentation, and resources from one of the best design teams on the planet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2012/01/ux-research-plan-stakeholders-love/&quot;&gt;The UX Research Plan That Stakeholders Love&lt;/a&gt;: UX leader Tomer Sharon shares a concise and powerful way to think about, frame, and share projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uxbooth.com/articles/complete-beginners-guide-to-design-research/&quot;&gt;Complete Beginner’s Guide to UX Research&lt;/a&gt;: The fine folks at UX Booth put together a great introduction to UX research, ranging from methods and tools to books and people to follow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/practical-design-discovery&quot;&gt;Practical Design Discovery&lt;/a&gt;: Dan Brown’s second chapter, “Frame the Problem,” provides a concise overview of practical design research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated April 28, 2017 to include&lt;/em&gt; Practical Design Discovery &lt;em&gt;by  Dan Brown.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 09:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/18/resources.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/11/18/resources.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Before You Even Open Your Mouth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For Optimal Workshop’s ebook &lt;em&gt;How to conduct great user interviews&lt;/em&gt; I contributed a chapter on reading the wider environment around your research focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The sights and sounds you capture add color, depth, and detail to your interview, which can be used to e ectively design and market the right products to the right audience. It’s a practice that top companies like &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/ikea-world-domination/&quot;&gt;Ikea&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3040223/when-it-clicks-it-clicks&quot;&gt;Lego&lt;/a&gt; perform to great success; both companies have incorporated home visits and observations into their respective research arsenals to refine their product lines and how they display said products.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By observing and documenting everything, you’re able to flesh out the interview with all-important details that ground your findings in context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://go.optimalworkshop.com/ebook/how-to-conduct-great-user-interviews&quot;&gt;Download the ebook&lt;/a&gt; to read my chapter, &lt;em&gt;Before you even open your mouth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/10/16/mouth.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/10/16/mouth.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Listen Hard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. It takes effort, patience, and practice. All at once, you’re taking in a narrative, providing cues that you’re engaged (nodding, saying “um-hmm”), analyzing what’s taking place, mulling over cogent responses, and mentally filing away bits to return to later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing so professionally adds additional tasks: documenting everything, missing nothing, and staying somewhat on course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reading about interview techniques, I came across another way to listen: the &lt;strong&gt;voice-relational analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. Typically this happens after an interview is completed—when you’re reviewing transcripts. But perform this analysis enough and you begin to do so &lt;em&gt;while listening&lt;/em&gt;, giving you a more accurate perspective on what you’re hearing, and directions for new questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the voice-relational analysis works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Listen for plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what you’re already doing—you’re capturing the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Listen for voice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say we’re talking about software, and I ask, “What apps do you use?” Here’s a typical response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I use Gmail and Evernote. Oh, and we also use Microsoft Word.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shift from “I” to “We” is telling—this person expresses personal preference versus organizational requirements by shifting voice. She likes Gmail and Evernote, but her company has saddled everyone with Word. (Of course, this might not be the entire story, but now we have an opportunity to explore further.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Listen for roles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the same answer above, we can determine the role of the person we’re listening to. The statement, “We use Microsoft Word,” seems to imply that selecting Word was &lt;em&gt;someone else’s&lt;/em&gt; choice. We can begin to form an org chart in our heads, and this person is not at the top. (Again, this might not be entirely true, but it provides us with more questions as we listen further.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening for role tells us who is empowered, versus who is not in a position of authority. If you’re trying to sell a product, or determine who might be authorized to make a purchase, this is solid gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening is hard, but so crucial. Listen hard enough and you’ll gain empathy and understanding. You’ll hear what you need to build the right experience for the right person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 10:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/22/listen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/22/listen.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everything is Important</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of my days interviewing people. Or rather, listening to people—coworkers, customers, and professional colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these conversations stem from a research project, or a desire to improve my research skills. Regardless, I approach my interviews with the mindset that &lt;strong&gt;everything is important, until proven otherwise.&lt;/strong&gt; I believe this mantra makes me a better researcher, and provides me with better research findings. Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If everything is important, I don’t want to miss a thing&lt;/strong&gt;. I stay on my toes, enthralled by every single thing I’m hearing. If it’s important enough that someone is sharing it with me, it’s important enough to receive my undivided, enthusiastic attention.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If everything is important, I’m disinclined to steer the conversation in a selfish direction&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s not to say I throw my own interview goals out the window, but I favor the direction set forth by my participant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If everything is important, the conversation holds meaning for us both&lt;/strong&gt;. My participant has a partner in me who can listen, reflect, validate, and elicit further thoughts. I get to learn something, and exit the conversation more insightful than I entered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mindset scales beyond conversations. A couple of years ago I described how I apply it to all sorts of data—like support emails and analytics—in &lt;a href=&quot;http://us5.campaign-archive1.com/?awesome=no&amp;amp;u=7e093c5cf4&amp;amp;id=361d158320&quot;&gt;Radicalizing Data&lt;/a&gt;. Simon Ouderkirk of WordPress &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.helpscout.net/blog/using-support-data-you-have/&quot;&gt;shares a similar philosophy&lt;/a&gt; of “assuming best intent” and maintaining “optimistic curiosity” in his wonderful post for Help Scout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By embracing optimism, we invest in the belief that what’s in front of us holds meaning.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s too easy to become calcified, to assume that we’ve heard it all before, to judge rather than journal. The best case scenario to assuming importance is that we gain wisdom and empathy. There is no worst case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 10:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/07/everything.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/07/everything.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stars, Ships, and Expectations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The products we use are the result of countless compromises and tradeoffs before we even experience them. Every engineering specification, and every design decision, stem from discussions we’re not privy to about form, time, effort, budget, and so many other considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a product is brought forth into the world, our individual experiences with it introduce context and variables that can stretch far beyond what its designers envisioned. How I use a product differs from how you use it, where you use it, when you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say this because last week, I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;/2016-06-14-android-future/&quot;&gt;the anti-experience&lt;/a&gt; of the Android operating system. My thesis was that Android is a loose collection of disparate experiences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devolute&quot;&gt;@devolute&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RWD&quot;&gt;@RWD&lt;/a&gt; The right UX shouldn&amp;#39;t be a game of Android Lotto.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gregg Bernstein (@greggcorp) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/greggcorp/status/748179776477798400&quot;&gt;June 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the thoughtful decisions that yielded the latest Android operating system, every phone carrier, manufacturer, and model adds a variable that yields vastly different outputs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beep&quot;&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt; added the technical context I had neglected by linking to the slide deck in this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-cards=&quot;hidden&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“If somebody tells you they tested their website on Android, laugh evilly and show them this slidedeck.”&lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/T14Upqoym5&quot;&gt;http://t.co/T14Upqoym5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;p much&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Responsive Design (@RWD) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RWD/status/488782076502896640&quot;&gt;July 14, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: the best possible version of Android is doomed to failure by an impossibility of contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian Parr responded to my article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RWD&quot;&gt;@RWD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/greggcorp&quot;&gt;@greggcorp&lt;/a&gt; I presume you’ve been told that you bought the wrong Android phone if you wanted the unified experience you talk about&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; devolute (@devolute) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devolute/status/748177489785163776&quot;&gt;June 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Jiri Jerabek wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/greggcorp&quot;&gt;@greggcorp&lt;/a&gt; Nexus is Google&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;North Star&amp;#39; for 3rd parties. I&amp;#39;m not sure whether what you described is a &amp;#39;problem&amp;#39; for the majority of users.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jiri Jerabek (@JiriJerabek) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JiriJerabek/status/748195407730180096&quot;&gt;June 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Ian and Jiri raise interesting points about the roles of North Stars and flagships, and where reasonable expectations give way to diminishing returns. A design &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass/designs-north-star-d469193063c5#.7ggv7r5te&quot;&gt;North Star&lt;/a&gt;, as described by Facebook’s Julie Zhou, is an achievable, realistic, inspiring, and unifying vision. At its core, a North Star provides internal guidance to the team building a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inversely, a flagship is the brand or service for which a company is most well known. The flagship is determined by audience size, sales figures, or popularity. &lt;strong&gt;It’s an outcome, not a goal.&lt;/strong&gt; The Accord is Honda’s flagship automobile, just as the Air Jordan remains Nike’s flagship shoe and Windows arguably represents Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all eyes on a flagship, it’s incumbent on a company to reserve their latest innovations for these popular offerings. In Android’s case, we can see that updating their flagship Nexus phones has two potential goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It signals that Google isn’t resting on its laurels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It introduces a halo effect for the rest of the brand. That is, what’s seen in the Nexus is reflected to varying degrees in offerings from Samsung, HTC, Motorola, and on down the line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this illustrates the difficult position Android finds itself in, as their flagship Nexus phones are &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; positioned as partner-facing North Stars: beacons of achievable, realistic &lt;em&gt;possibilities&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But possibilities yield to &lt;em&gt;expectations&lt;/em&gt;. The expectation is that the innovations in the flagship will surface elsewhere, which for an Android purchaser is a risky proposition. What appears in the flagship, however tightly correlated to the North Star that brought it to life, has no guarantee of trickling down to mass production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 10:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/06/stars-ships.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/06/stars-ships.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
