<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gregg Bernstein | gregg.io</title>
    <description>User &amp;amp; Product Researcher &amp;bull; Writer &amp;amp; Editor &amp;bull; Speaker &amp;amp; Educator
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 08:25:23 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 08:25:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facebook's News Trustworthiness Survey</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, I wrote about Facebook’s news trustworthiness survey. While its brevity is gaining attention, the real issue with the Facebook survey is poor editing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For their paean to minimalism, I salute the team behind this survey. However, the problem here isn’t that the survey is short. Rather, the two survey questions are phrased poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to take a second to admit how surreal it is to open this update with “For &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.” When I was finishing grad school, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; launched. I knew immediately that it would become one of my favorite websites, and came very, very close to introducing myself via email to see what use they might have for a UX researcher or designer. That I ended up working with and contributing to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; a few short years later is a career highlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/26/16933458/facebook-news-trust-survey-problems-editing&quot;&gt;Read the entire post on &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 04:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/26/facebook-survey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/26/facebook-survey.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stop Pretending</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re asking participants to guess, predict, hypothesize, or anticipate either their future behavior or that of a friend, you’re not researching. You’re pretending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be it an interview or a survey, ask your participants about &lt;strong&gt;past actions and behaviors&lt;/strong&gt;. This eliminates aspirational responses (&lt;em&gt;Yes, I would pay money for this app&lt;/em&gt;) and answers designed to please you, the researcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A safe bet is to eschew any questions that begin with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;How likely are you to… ?&lt;/code&gt; The framing of this question eliminates any burden on the participant to answer based on evidence or past behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple fix is to replace &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;How likely are you to… ?&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Have you ever… ?&lt;/code&gt; For example, when my colleagues proposed a NPS (Net Promoter Score) question for a survey, I countered with an evidence-based approach. Instead of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;How likely are you to recommend Polygon to a friend or family member?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Have you ever recommended Polygon to a friend or family member?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed this up with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/code&gt;
It’s a small change that provides both a measure of and the impetus for said recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is a time and place for research based on guesses and projections, but it’s not in a survey or interview. Design walkthroughs and participatory design sessions, among others, offer opportunities to ask tightly scoped questions and collaboratively work through ideas. But here again, the participants should be those who can anchor their responses in past experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are capable of building amazing products and experiences that exceed the expectations of our users and customers, but those experiences begin with a solid foundation based in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 04:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/14/stop-pretending.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/14/stop-pretending.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scope and Scale</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I used to be fascinated by nearby houses obscured by foliage and fences. Or the long driveways that disappeared into the distance. Where did they go? What was out there? &lt;em&gt;Who&lt;/em&gt; was out there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew the hidden houses were likely no different than those I could plainly see. And the people within were probably similar to the neighbors next door. But without seeing those houses, and without knowing those occupants, I couldn’t be sure. I was in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I did after the launch of Google Maps was to virtually fly over the streets of my youth, and solve the mysteries of the hidden houses. Finally, my unanswerable questions could be easily answered. I followed long driveways to small ranch houses. Forested lots yielded to clearings containing some of the oldest homes in the area. Privacy fences no longer served their intended purpose, and I was finally able to see a holistic view of my old neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my work as a researcher, I have a tendency to think of the data I need in much the same way I thought about the houses of my youth: it might be fenced off or hidden, but it’s there. And once I find it, I will have a clearer picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within every organization, there’s plenty of information for the taking. Some of it is in plain sight. Some is easily obtained by asking. But some of the data is siloed. Or lost. Or not recognized as something worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can go crazy trying to accumulate every piece of data–the customer feedback, the survey responses, the sales figures, the NPS scores, the old interview transcripts… there’s always another piece to the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing: product research is not a puzzle to be solved—it’s a journey. I don’t need the complete picture; &lt;strong&gt;I only need a direction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; the entire map of my neighborhood. I got around just fine. Some data might be enough data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/08/scope-and-scale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/08/scope-and-scale.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Field Means Proximity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my role as a researcher on a product team, I spend a lot of time talking to users. It’s always a worthy endeavor—I get to learn about workflows, habits, and the larger context surrounding the person I’m speaking with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fieldwork, however, takes those talks and enhances them. Fieldwork offers proximity, and proximity unlocks everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A funny thing happens the longer you spend in close proximity with someone—your connection strengthens. You develop a rapport and a sense of trust. Only once this sense of trust is established does honesty emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate, here’s a very unscientific chart that you will not see in the &lt;em&gt;New England Journal of Product Research&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/chart.png&quot; alt=&quot;An unscientific chart about research proximity.&quot; title=&quot;An unscientific chart about research proximity&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I managed MailChimp’s research practice, we performed field studies often. A few years ago, a fellow researcher and I were in Denver, Colorado to visit customers at their respective workplaces. We spent roughly half a day with each customer, learning about their companies and roles and where our product fit in. These hours were uniformly educational—we left each visit with new insights to share with colleagues back at HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two visits from this trip stand out. On our first morning in Denver, our very first visit was with an ecommerce startup. After a bit of small talk and an hour of conversation about his business, our customer suddenly said that he wasn’t sure he would remain a customer much longer. He was looking at competitors and planning to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had just presented his ecommerce and marketing operations to us, and described where our product fit in. But he went on to explain that our competitors offered a host of features that we couldn’t match. While disappointing to hear, it was helpful information to understand the process our customer went through to even arrive at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we visited another customer—a high profile and, by all appearances, model customer. Again, after over an hour of small and shop talk, this customer too announced that he had been thinking of leaving. And he explained his ambitious marketing plans and the tools offered by our competitors and the ways in which we (seemingly) didn’t stack up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose to visit the specific customers on this trip because they &lt;em&gt;seemed&lt;/em&gt; to be doing everything right, and using our product to great success. But had we not visited their offices, over a thousand miles away from MailChimp HQ, we would never have known why they left. We would never have gotten their perspective on why we were no longer the right fit going forward. Instead of being in the dark, we had explanations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this came about because of proximity—because we set aside time to enter the field, gave our undivided attention to our customers, and provided our conversations room to breathe and meander and hold meaning. The proximity of field work pays off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more on fieldwork, see my recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-field-study-handbook/the-field-test-5a243e71ff35&quot;&gt;Medium post for Jan Chipchase’s Field Study Handbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/06/proximity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/06/proximity.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make Stability a Priority</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Boston Celtics are a professional basketball team. What you might not know is that the Celtics are also an exemplar of organizational management. From their front office operation to their on-court product, the Celtics maintain an org structure that attracts great talent from top to bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Celtics, in how they run their organization, &lt;strong&gt;make stability a priority&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Product management is product management, whether the product is a basketball team or an app or a service. So what makes the Celtics’ management stand out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their ownership group is &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt;. You don’t hear of petty squabbles among their key executives. Their leadership is collaborative, supportive, and tenured. General manager Danny Ainge has been at the helm since 2003, and will be in place for the foreseeable future. Head coach Brad Stevens, 40, arrived in 2013 to replace Doc Rivers, who had run the team since 2004. Stevens is set to remain in his position for as long as he wants. Leaders remain with the Celtics—they’re a destination, not a stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Ainge empowered to work without fear of impetuous ownership, and Stevens unleashed to coach unfettered from  capricious management, the team simply wins. And they win because their leadership is mandated to set longterm strategy, recruit players that execute that strategy, and coach and mentor to fulfill that strategy. It’s a stable operating environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When meeting with prospective players, Ainge and Stevens can talk up their talented roster. They can show off their facilities. But the calm of stability is a competitive advantage that few rival teams can match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what makes for a stable organization?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable organizations minimize upheaval&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steady leadership and a thoughtful division of labor and practices mitigate stress and churn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable organizations form and execute a longterm strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid strategy maximizes planning and minimizes surprise. It allows for the growth and development of everyone from individual contributors to managers and executives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable organizations pace themselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stability begets an implicit understanding of a normal workflow and workload for everyone within an organization. That steady workflow prevents exhaustion, burnout, and churn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stability informs every facet of every part of an organization, and the best orgs make stability a priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I first learned of the Celtics’ belief in stability as a priority from a 2016 podcast with ESPN’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinarnovitz&quot;&gt;Kevin Arnovitz&lt;/a&gt; (the link to which I cannot find).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/stability-priority.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/stability-priority.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Field Test</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.studiodradiodurans.com/&quot;&gt;Jan Chipchase&lt;/a&gt; is an authority on qualitative product research. He embeds himself in the field with a team of colleagues and fixers, capturing the context and ecosystems in which people live. He’s the type of researcher I want to be when I grow up—traveling to the far corners of the earth to uncover hidden truths and potential opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan’s taken his experiences and created the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/janchipchase/the-field-study-handbook&quot;&gt;Field Study Handbook&lt;/a&gt;. It was a career highlight to work with Jan as a technical reviewer on a few chapters of the handbook, and I’m excited for the book’s release in June, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we get closer to the book’s launch, I contributed a short piece about what you learn about a product research team in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The field, though, is opportunity. Exiting the office and entering the field introduces novelty, variety, and a chance for adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-field-study-handbook/the-field-test-5a243e71ff35&quot;&gt;The Field Test&lt;/a&gt; on Medium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/field.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/field.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UX Research Templates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Vox Product blog, I wrote about how I create an &lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2017/4/19/15309792/ambient-ux-research&quot;&gt;ambient awareness of user and product research&lt;/a&gt; across my product team by sharing everything, everywhere—repeatedly and redundantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my sharing takes place over Slack and in Google Docs, and a few people asked me to &lt;strong&gt;share my research doc templates&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I share notes from a single interview or usability test in Slack, I keep things simple with a bolded headline and a handful of bullet points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/slack_template.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of how I share quick takeaways in Slack.&quot; title=&quot;An example of how I share quick takeaways in Slack.&quot; /&gt;
I want my colleagues to be aware of what I just learned, and who I learned it from. I try to anonymize participants in Slack by only referring to their role, not their name. Because I work with many internal users, I want to avoid bringing undue attention on any one person. (I also want to avoid interrupting their work by inadvertently summoning them to the Slack channel!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-doc&quot;&gt;Google Doc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to collecting findings into a more permanent document, I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1yuTzHv47qCRbqbcdzu8subZpbKXfCXNglsvkjCYIM-w/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;this Google Doc template&lt;/a&gt; as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep reports as brief as possible, and open the doc with &lt;strong&gt;recommendations and issues&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s what people want to see, so why make them work to find it? Placing the recommendations at the top also makes it possible to review the findings by previewing (rather than opening) the file in Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google_template.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of how I structure takeaways in Google Docs.&quot; title=&quot;An example of how I structure takeaways in Google Docs.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then explain how I tested (remotely or IRL; with a prototype or something that’s been released) and recap each individual test or interview (almost verbatim from what I shared in Slack, perhaps with a few more details).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I use a &lt;strong&gt;Metadata&lt;/strong&gt; section to share the project genesis, goals, methodology, participants, script, schedule, and recruiting pitches. The metadata is meant to allow anyone to follow my steps, validate my work, or repeat the research process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This metadata section will look familiar to anyone who’s seen Tomer Sharon’s wonderful &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2012/01/ux-research-plan-stakeholders-love/&quot;&gt;UX Research Plan That Stakeholders Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;—I folded in a modified version of Tomer’s plan so this doc can serve as a proposal, a plan, or an archive depending on the stage of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alignment&quot;&gt;Alignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listed Slack and Google Docs as the media of choice for my organization. The important thing to note is that the medium you use is entirely dependent on your organization’s habits. If your org runs on Basecamp, or a combination of HipChat + Confluence, go that route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you’ll want to dismantle these templates and reassemble them to serve and inform your particular colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-me&quot;&gt;@ Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to see how different organizations capture and share information. If you have templates or recommendations you want to share, tweet at or email me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/25/templates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/25/templates.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ambient Research</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Vox Product blog, I describe how I create an &lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2017/4/19/15309792/ambient-ux-research&quot;&gt;ambient awareness of user and product research&lt;/a&gt; across my product team by sharing everything, everywhere—repeatedly and redundantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By showing my work everywhere and often, my colleagues see that research isn’t a “when we have the time” activity—it’s habitual and ongoing. Ideally, every project should bake in research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear to me that sharing findings in a way that makes them discoverable and teachable across an organization is the biggest challenge research teams face. Expect more thoughts on containing research in upcoming posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2017/4/19/15309792/ambient-ux-research&quot;&gt;Read the entire post on the Vox Product blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 07:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/ambient.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/ambient.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capture the Context</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Optimal Workshop blog, I explain that there’s so much more to interviews than asking and answering in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.optimalworkshop.com/capture-the-context-pro-tips-for-user-interviews&quot;&gt;Capture the Context&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stories convey so much. The best stories contain enough rich, lived-in detail to elicit understanding and empathy. These contextual details flesh out words and actions, anchoring the story in place and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.optimalworkshop.com/capture-the-context-pro-tips-for-user-interviews&quot;&gt;Read the entire post on the Optimal Workshop blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 06:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/30/capture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/30/capture.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Parts Bin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you propose something to your colleagues, but it’s not met with much enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a good design isn’t quite good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes a great idea works well on its own but not in concert with other parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could choose to see these as setbacks or disappointments. &lt;em&gt;Or you could see them as parts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when I worked at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;, I was introduced to the concept of the &lt;strong&gt;parts bin&lt;/strong&gt; by our CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/benchestnut&quot;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;. To Ben, every design or prototype held merit, regardless of whether it amounted to anything. At some point, those half-baked designs would become valuable in service to even better ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts bin became a research mindset for me and others at the company, as evidenced by our adoption of Evernote as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/connected-ux&quot;&gt;repository for anything research-related&lt;/a&gt;. A stray data point might not be useful today, but we figured it would be useful to &lt;em&gt;someone, someday&lt;/em&gt;. As I’ve written before, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gregg.io/2016/07/07/everything.html&quot;&gt;everything is important&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts bin applies beyond design and research. When you frame your ideas as parts to be broken down and reconfigured time and time again, they become less precious and more practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to hold onto them, and come up with a bin that works. Without the bin to document your ideas, parts will disappear into the ether. To that end, I want to share how I’ve set up my parts bin (or &lt;em&gt;bins&lt;/em&gt;, in my case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideas-and-inputs&quot;&gt;Ideas and Inputs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I break my parts bins across two dimensions: &lt;strong&gt;ideas and inputs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I have an &lt;strong&gt;idea&lt;/strong&gt;, I’m excited and need to capture it in a way that’s lightweight and actionable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I come across context for an idea—be it an article, data visualization, document, or whatever—that’s an &lt;strong&gt;input&lt;/strong&gt; that I need to tag and archive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ideas, I rely on Wunderlist. This app allows me to keep multiple lists, with each list affording subtasks and a notes field. I keep a lot of lists, including people to talk to, articles to read, and posts I want to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the latter, I have dozens of writing ideas. Each idea typically contains a few points I want to make, along with a sentence (or a string of words) to help me remember the context in which I came up with the idea. For this post, the list looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wl.png&quot; alt=&quot;This list hints at the structural pieces for this post—Ben at MailChimp, Wunderlist, Evernote, etc.&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot of Wunderlist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lean on Evernote for inputs. For instance, I’ve been studying cognitive interviews lately—a technique wonderfully documented in this recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2016/05/how-to-interrogate-suspects/&quot;&gt;Wired article&lt;/a&gt;. As I come across more literature on this topic, into my Evernote notebooks it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two repositories, or &lt;em&gt;parts bins&lt;/em&gt;, give me dozens of starting points and hundreds of supporting documents. And with a mindset that all of this will—in some way—prove useful, it’s a rewarding habit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 09:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/20/parts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/11/20/parts.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
